Chapter 1: Avada Kedavra

This is a spin off of Less Wrongs Harry Potter and the Methods of Rationality Fanfiction. All idea's and characters go to him and J.K. Rowling. I just couldn't resist jumping in on the fun.

If you have not read Methods of Rationality, please stop what you are doing and read it NOW! It is awesomeness in a can.

And now, please enjoy my fanfiction, of a fanfiction.

Truemythewise: *sigh*

Inner child: *pressing hands over mouth, hardly restraining utter delight*

Truemythewise: "I suppose this is it…" *starts adjusting a rather thick rope into a noose.* "I never thought I'd let it get this horrible."

Inner child: "Oh, shut up, you know you're going to enjoy this!"

Truemythewise: "Yes," *nestling noose around neck* "I just never thought my descent into complete nerdom would ever happen. I mean, I'm past the point of no return once I do this." *Taking a deep breath.* "Alright. I'm going to do it. I'm going to do the unspeakable. I'm—" *swallows* "I'm going to write a fanfiction of a fanficiton!" *Promptly kicks chair out from under herself.*

Inner child: *cheers in delight* "Oh, this is going to be so much fun!"

Dignity: *shoulders slumped, dragging own noose behind.* "We had a line that we just did not cross. There is only so much you can do before you are a hopeless nerd." *rightens knocked over chair next to Truemythewise's swinging corpse* "And this is one of those things" *sets up own noose*

Inner child: *dancing and whooping in victory about the pair doomed personalities*

Dignity: "You are far too happy about this."

Inner child: "Oh please she's been wanting to do this for years. Just imagine FINALLY getting all those stories out of your head onto paper. No need to worry about being original this is going to be fun!"

Dignity: "Course you don't care about originality." *tightens noose around throat while continuing speaking* "I just don't see the point in writing off someone else's perfectly good work. The only reason why anyone would do such a thing is because they couldn't come up with anything awesome on their own."

Inner child: "Nonsense. There are plenty of original fanficiton's that are awesome in their own right. Besides, fanficition isn't about being original it's about going with it and having fun! Dignity be hanged!"

Dignity: *is promptly hanged*

Inner child: *cheers in victory* "Let the lord of chaos rule!"

Chapter one

Avada Kedavra

The day had arrived when Harry would learn the curse that had set into action his epic destiny to become the world's first immortal magical scientist. (or so he hoped anyway.) Today was the day he'd learn the infamous, unbeatable, unblockable, one hit KO Avada Kedavra. Today he'd see just how accurate Professor Quirrell hypothesis of Harry's intent to kill really was. Today…was going to suck.

It was going to suck for two reasons. One, if he successfully learned Avada Kedavra it'd be plus fifty points to dark lord Harry's reputation, which, after the incident with the bullies, had significantly grown. It didn't help that there were only five people in the entire world, including himself, who knew he could cast a Patronus. If Harry learned Avada Kedavra in his first year and not be capable of producing a Patronus, that was indeed a sure sign of him being a dark wizard. Oh, and he'd almost been sorted into Slytherin.

And two, today was going to suck because Professor Quirrell had decided he needed help in teaching the children of Hogwarts Avada Kedavra, and who better to fulfill the roll of assistance to death than Lucius Malfoy.

There were probably a host of other reasons why today was going to suck, but at the moment Harry couldn't think of them.

The extra credit lesson was set in the Defense Against the Dark Arts classroom. Harry sat in his usual seat in the back of the room, waiting for the Defense Professor to finish his 'security speech.' It wasn't very long.

"This is the killing curse. It kills people. When you cast this curse and hit your intended target do not be shocked to find them dead. I repeat, this is the killing curse. You do not use this curse unless you mean to kill someone."

Harry almost snorted, but too many people had decided to sit close to him today. As if his supposed immunity to the killing curse could somehow protect them. Most of them were Hufflepuffs, and a surprising number of Gryffindors.

"There are a number of useful way's to go about this curse, but until you have experience with it, stick to the notion that when firing this curse, expect people to die. Now, if there is anyone in the room who is uncomfortable with the current curriculum, I invite you to leave now."

Several students looked to one another, but no one rose. Harry's eyes drifted to Hermione. All he could make out was the back of her bushy head, but he could imagine the determined look on her face. Harry didn't think she had it in her to kill someone, but he knew she'd want to try and learn the spell anyway. Perhaps she even fooled herself into thinking she could do it, and maybe she could. Harry hoped that she wouldn't learn though. There was just something wrong with teaching Hermione Granger to kill people.

"Alright, I'm going to demonstrate the spell three times and then you are going to take it in turns coming up and trying it for yourselves," a twisted smile came to the Defense Professors lips. "Any volunteers?"

Several people scooted closer to Harry.

Professor Quirrell waved and three caged rats resting on pedestals appeared. He went through the gesture of the spell twice before uttering it.

"Avada Kedavra."

A flash of green light and the first rat was dead.

"The key to the killing curse is intent. You have to mean to kill." He performed the gestures again, slowly for every first year to catch. And with the flick of his wand, an incantation, and the second rat was dead.

"I doubt there are many of you who will succeed in casting so much as a flicker of light, of those who do manage to get that far, do not be too disappointed to find your intended target very much alive," The Defense Professor went on before casting the curse a third time, finishing off the last rat. "Like anything, the spell takes practice and a certain mindset." He gestured and the three cages containing dead rats vanished. "Rise."

The class did so, and just as soon as Harry's feet hit the ground the desks before the first years vanished. At the front of the class room stood twenty pedestals containing live caged rats. Professor Quirrell had the people closest try their hand at the spell. Between him, and Lucius Malfoy, it took the whole of five minutes to instruct and correct the children's gestures before having them actually perform the spell, wands clearly pointing at the rats, and no one else.

There was a chorus of "Avada Kedavra" at which no rat was killed, not even a flicker of light. The first years looked to one another, not sure what to expect. Professor Quirrell had them try five more times before switching to the next group. While the next group was instructed, Lucius Malfoy set about the classroom, speaking to clusters of children before they were called up.

Harry couldn't imagine what sort of instruction Lucius would be giving. It seemed it'd be some time before he'd reach Harry and the crowd of Hufflepuffs and Gryffindors that were drawing closer and closer to him. If they came any nearer they'd be huddled right next to him. It was as if they completely forgot the whole affair with Tracy Davis, or perhaps it was because of that.

Blaise Zabini was among the first to issue a spray of green light from his wand. He smirked with pride and welcomed the applause from the Slytherin's, but his flash was followed by Draco's spark that actually went a few feet before fading. Draco looked up and met Harry's eyes with a grin before taking his seat amongst the Slytherins and those who had not tried, or not succeeded from that house quickly congregated around him. A surprising number of Ravenclaw's did as well.

Tracy Davis managed something of a squirt her third attempt, and sneered at the classmates who'd failed next to her, but she wasn't the only one having success. A number of Ravenclaws and a handful of Gryffindors were producing flickers of light as well. It seemed Lucius's instruction was indeed helpful. And by the time he reached the back row, Harry was quite interested what advice he had to give.

However, upon reaching the group of nervous looking Hufflepuffs and Gryffindors, Malfoy only sneered at them and said. "I know a lost cause when I see one," and turned to go.

"Hang on," Harry said, though part of him shared the relief with the first years gathered round. However, his curiosity wouldn't settle for it. "I'd like to hear what you told everyone else."

Lucius turned and regarded Harry. "The spell might come easier to those who have some understanding of death," his eyes flickered to the rest of the first years. "If any of you have family to suffer from this past war, thinking of them might prove helpful." And with that, he turned and strode away.

Harry wondered at that piece of advice. How would thinking of someone you'd rather be alive help you kill? Maybe he'd said it to be deliberately unhelpful. Harry was about to go and ask Tracy what Malfoy had told her, but his group was called next to the front.

It seemed the aura of doom was particularly strong today. Harry had only crossed halfway to the pedestals before he felt the beginnings of it. It was almost an intolerable distraction when he reached the pedestal. If the Defense Professor noticed the strain, he gave no sign of it. However, he did keep a greater distance from the rest of the students than he had with the others who'd come forward.

As with the other first years, Professor Quirrell had them master the gesture before attempting the spell.

Any advice? Harry asked his inner circle.

Why waste time bothering with us? You know what you have to do. Quipped Slytherin. Only Ravenclaw was in disagreement, but that was only because it wanted to see if not consulting his dark side would produce different results.

"Avada Kedavra!"

Harry had missed the first try. He hadn't seen any flashes of light to either side of him, but that might have been because people were once again watching to see how he'd do on the extracurricular spell.

"Please, focus on your own wand work. Potter, I take a point from Ravenclaw for lack of effort. Again."

Okay. Harry didn't close his eyes. He started the gesture, along with everyone else, eyes focused on the rat. He needed to get angry. What could possibly set him off enough to make him want to break his resolution that everyone ought to live forever?

Please, not Harry! Take me! Take me instead!

Very well, I accept the bargain. Yourself to die, and the child to live. Now drop your wand so that I can murder you.

His blood temperature was dropping rapidly, all this came to him in the matter of seconds it took to get halfway through the first gestures of the spell.

There is nothing human left in him. Him you must destroy. You must not hesitate, when the time comes. To him alone, of all the creatures in this world, you must show no mercy; and when you are done you must forget it, forget that you ever did such a thing, and go back to living. Save your fury for that, and that alone.

He remembered the crimson eyes, the voice of death, and the high cold laugh. Oddly it was not fiery rage that filled Harry the moment before he released the spell. In that moment, just when his temperature seemed to hit somewhere in the negatives, he felt no anger at all as his dark side stirred and took over.

The rat needed killing. That was all.

"Avadakedavra," the spell ran off as one word from Harry's lips, seamless and complete. And it came as no surprise to him to see the jet of green light issue out of the end of his wand and strike the rat. It did not so much as squeak before going limp.

And Harry felt nothing. No simmering rage. No ominous resolution. The rat was dead. Harry had willed it to die, and so it did.

(1) (not word for word but still) Chapter 43: Humanism, Pt 1 - Less Wrong Harry Potter and the Methods of Rationality

(2) Chapter 43: Humanism, Pt 1 - Less Wrong Harry Potter and the Methods of Rationality

(3) Chapter 76: SA After, Surface Appearances - Harry Potter and the Methods or Rationality

Chapter 8: The Pact

Hey, just wanted to first give a shout out to Less Wrong, and whoever runs The Methods or Rationality webpage. Just wanted to say thank you for adding Dark Lord Material to the list of fanfictions. I wasn't expecting that. Though I'm sure you people do it for every fanfiction for Methods or Rationality, but still its a cool of you to do that. So... THANK YOU!

Anyway, here are chapter.

Thanks Theonebutcher for the name of the book.

Chapter Eight

The Pact

To avoid having to deal with the now not so frightened student body of Hogwarts, Harry left the Great Hall earlier than he usually would have. Greenhouse One was not located within the castle and only a complete idiot would get lost finding it, especially after spending over a semester at Hogwarts. Otherwise, Harry might have used that excuse and purposely arrived late for class just to further put off the host of overly curious students who would not be so easily deterred to interview him.

Harry arrived at Greenhouse one early, early enough that even Professor Sprout had not arrived to prepare the day's lesson. The Greenhouse was locked, so he couldn't even go in there and pretend to be doing something productive. Instead he plopped down on the ground and pulled out 'One Thousand Magical Herbs and Fungi' and began sifting through it, not really taking anything in. He'd already read the book entirely twice and it wasn't because he enjoyed it ever so much. He had rushed through it so quickly the first time he hardly remembered a word of it, not that he'd ever admit that to Hermione.

Hermione… He was more than a little concerned with what she would try to get him out of detention. At least he could trust that she wouldn't do anything too drastic. She was a rule abiding student after all… uh maybe not anymore.

The sounds of someone approaching caught Harry's attention and without thinking he looked up from 'One Thousand Magical Herbs and Fungi'. Draco Malfoy and his two goons were making their way towards the Greenhouse, the first from Slytherin to arrive that day. At a gesture from Draco, Crabbe and Goyle stopped, crossed their arms, and frowned menacingly at nobody.

Draco continued to Harry, who watched his approach with an expression that made it clear he didn't want to be talked to right now. Draco didn't even pause, just blundered over to Harry, drew out his wand, and said, "Quietus."

"What do you want?" Harry said, none too kindly.

Draco frowned, but other than that gave no more notice of Harry's tone. "We need to talk."

"We're talking," Harry said irritably and looked back down at his book.

"I mean privately."

"No one's around."

"Look, Potter, this is important," something in Draco's tone gave Harry pause, but he did not look up from his book nor did he reply. "Meet me-"

"No," Harry said cutting him off. Despite Harry's mood, his inner Slytherin hissed at him.

What are you doing? This is a Malfoy, not some over egger Gryffindor, or skimpy Hufflpuff. Apologize!

Bugger off! Harry said. Such was his state that he couldn't even be civil with his own imaginary personalities.

"No?" Draco repeated, and Harry, knowing Draco quite well, picked up the edge of annoyance.

"I don't have time," Harry said curtly.

"Then make time," Draco hissed, losing civility himself. "This is important."

"Just tell me now, no one's around."

"I can't just-" Draco took a breath. He bent over, placing a hand on the Greenhouse wall that Harry was propped up against. He leaned over Harry in a threatening manner and if anyone had been watching they would know that the scone of Malfoy was not just having a little chat with The Boy Who Lived before class. Luckily, no one was around, and when Draco next spoke Harry did look up. "It's about our pact," Draco whispered unnecessary.

Harry blinked, and slowly closed his book. He hadn't been expecting that topic to resurface anytime soon.

"What do you mean?" Harry said slowly.

"We can't talk here," Draco said and tried to give a time and meeting place again, but Harry cut him off.

"I'm sorry, Draco, but we have to talk here. I literally do not have the time to meet with you, so please make it quick." Harry said, just barely keeping his annoyance from his voice. It didn't come out apologetic, but at least he was no longer snapping at the hair of Malfoy.

Draco observed him a moment, still poised above, before removing his hand from the wall and squatted down in front of Harry. "Look," he whispered. "Father and I have a chance to unseat Dumbledore and if you want in I'd considered part of our pact fulfilled."

Alarm bells went off in Harry's head, blowing away his former sleep deprived bad mood. This was important and not something Harry could just back out of. If Lucius Malfoy was planning to kill Dumbledore…

"I haven't seen any evidence that shows the Headmaster did what he did," Harry whispered, forgetting that the action was completely unnecessary.

Draco's lip curled. "I thought you took our friendship seriously."

"I do," Harry insisted. "But, Draco, this is-"

"Important, yeah, I told you. Look, Harry, I'm fulfilling my part of the pact. I've started to at least try to restore Slytherin's name. What have you done? Have you put any effort at all into finding evidence? I'm sure it wouldn't be hard for you and your muggle science to find something."

That hurt. Part of Harry knew Draco was trying to manipulate him, or at least suspected he was, but it still hurt and it worked. Harry felt guilty. He really hadn't put any effort into looking up evidence on Dumbledore, and if he did value Draco's friendship he would have at least done that much.

Harry met Draco's disappointed look and he knew that Draco knew he hadn't and it just made him feel worse.

And for some reason Harry thought of Charles Horton Cooley theory 'The Looking Glass Self' which explains how a person's conception of self arises through considering our relationship to others. The theory develops from how we think we appear to others, how we think others judge us, and last how the first two make us feel. It involves perception and effect, the perception of how others see us and the effect of others judgment on us.

Even with this rationalization, Harry still felt guilty.

"Alright, but it's-" Harry began, but Goyle's shout "People coming!" cut him off, and Draco abruptly rose and strode casually over to Crabbe and Goyle.

The more eager Ravenclaw students arrived and Harry noted that Hermione was not among them, which gave him more cause for worry. Noticing the Ravenclaws had spotted him, Harry opened his book once more and made a point of ignoring them. Professor Sprout shortly showed up and opened the Greenhouse, after ten or so minutes the rest of the class arrived, well everyone besides Hermione and Padma, Daphne and Tracy.

The Professors lips pursed together when it was time for class and the girls still weren't there. And just as Harry was about to make an excuse to go look for them, the four girls stumbled into the room, almost one on top of the other and completely out of breath.

"Sorry," Padma panted.

"That's twenty points from Ravenclaw, and twenty points from Slytherin and should I learn you girls were starting trouble it'll be more than that," Professor Sprout said. There was a flicker of something in her facial expression, but it was gone and Harry was too distracted to think much of it.

The girls glanced at Hermione, but said nothing and took their usual seats.

Hermione offered no explanation or apology. She simply took a spot beside Harry, (eyeing down the poor Ravenclaw who'd been previously sitting next to him.)

As Professor Sprout started the lesson, Hermione whispered "Quietus," which surprised Harry, though at this point he really should have learned better. She turned to him and whispered. "We need to talk."

Harry stared at her.